clarinsusa.com 2018-10-21

# Privacy Policy - CLARINS

This Privacy Policy was updated on February 25, 2016 to include terms relative to our Facebook app.

#### 1 - Introduction

This Privacy Policy is applicable to all the services offered by, and the website www.clarinsusa.com operated by, the company Clarins USA, Inc., (“Clarins”), whose registered offices are located at 1 Park Avenue, 19th Floor, New York, NY 10016. Personal Information gathered about you and processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy is controlled by Clarins. 

Please read the following Privacy Policy to understand how we use your Personal Information (as defined under section 2 hereto) after it has been collected by us. Please read through this Privacy Policy before submitting any of your Personal Information to us.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy at any time, please send us an [email](mailto:help@clarinsusa.com).

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page. In case of such an update we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying you of the change. You will also be notified via email of the changes to the processing activities and asked for your consent. Your consent to the changes will be implied if you do not oppose to them within 30 days after you have been given notice.

#### 2 - When do we collect Personal Information?

“Personal Information” that we shall collect and process about you will consist of any information which refers to you personally and that may be generated though the above services or websites such as but not limited to your name, email address and postal address (as further developed under section 3 hereto). We collect Personal Information from you when you do the following through our website:

  * visit the website;
  * register on the website;
  * install our Facebook app;
  * order goods or services;
  * submit any other queries online.

#### 3 - What Personal Information do we collect from you?

We collect Personal Information from you including your:

  * name;
  * postal address;
  * phone number;
  * email address;
  * Facebook photos;
  * Credit card, debit card, or checking account information (including credit card number and expiration date);
  * transaction information (history and record of your purchases, payment information, invoices, after-sale services, etc.);
  * any other Personal Information provided by you;
  * your IP address, information about the websites you visit and your trends as a user as explained in section 7 and 9 of this Privacy Policy.

#### 4 - What do we do with your Personal Information?

When you give us any Personal Information as indicated above, we use your Personal Information to:

  * administer this website;
  * improve your browsing experience;
  * enable the use of the services made available on this website;
  * Facebook photos will be used for the sole purpose of creating your #worththewrinkle video;
  * confirm, process and track your orders for goods and services;
  * correspond with you about your orders;
  * deliver goods and services that you purchase online;
  * provide after sales services, handle goods returns, recalls;
  * send statements and invoices to you, and collect payments from you;
  * administer billing and payment for your purchases;
  * provide you, with your consent where required by law, with information by email, sms, mms, faxes, phone calls (automated or not), post, or any other communications means, about the latest news or special offers from Clarins which may be of interest to you unless you have opted to be excluded from these communications. This information will relate to the same products or similar products to those that you have purchased. You can inform us at any time and for free if you no longer wish to receive such information by sending us an [email](mailto:help@clarinsusa.com).
  * respond to your submitted queries.

#### 5 - Who do we pass your Personal Information to?

We may share Personal Information collected via the website with third party service providers who perform services on our behalf based on our instructions in order to help us to operate the website, process your orders and queries or otherwise manage the customer relationship between you and us. These third parties may be located in or out of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), including in countries that do not provide the same level of data protection as in your country of residence. In such a case, we will ensure either (i) to obtain your unambiguous consent to share your Personal Information with these third providers, (ii) to use third providers self-certified under the Safe Harbour Program, or (iii) to enter into appropriate data transfer agreements conforming to the Standard Model Clauses established by the European Commission, to the extent required by the applicable law. 

The Personal Information you submitted when you register on this website, when you buy a product from Clarins and the information concerning your use of the website will be shared with Clarins and any of its affiliated companies so that they can send you information about their products if you have consented by ticking the relevant box. These organisations belong to Clarins and the information that you will be sent will relate to their products only.

Otherwise, we will only disclose Personal Information to government bodies and law enforcement agencies, successors in title to our business, or in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, or to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to third parties for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk as permitted by law). In this case we will inform you about the disclosure and the entity we disclosed your Personal Information to.

#### 6 - Cookies and Web Beacons

When you view our websites we may store information on the hard drive of your computer in the form of a "cookie" (essentially a small text file or single GIF). Cookies allow us to tailor the websites to your interests and preferences. For example, a cookie might contain information about the web pages you have visited on the website, which could allow us to customise your next visit to the websites. However, cookies do not allow us access to the rest of your computer.

In order to analyze the success of our marketing campaigns, we also implement other technologies such as web beacons. We use third-party web beacons from Yahoo! to help analyze where visitors go and what they do while visiting our website. Yahoo! may also use anonymous information about your visits to this and other websites in order to improve its products and services and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Yahoo! please send us an [Email](mailto:help@clarinsusa.com).

Most Internet browsers enable you to delete cookies or to receive a warning before a cookie is stored on your hard drive. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about how to do this. However, should you decide to disable any cookies we place on your computer you may not be able to use certain services or facilities on the website.

#### 7 - Linking to other websites

The website contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These websites have their own privacy policies and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of Personal Information you submit whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

#### 8 - IP Addresses

We study visitor trends since we are interested in the successful dissemination of information through the websites. Our server creates log files of information such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address from your network, what pages were explored and the length of your visit.  Analysis software is used to generate reports which help us to learn more about how we can enhance your experience with the websites. This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you. The log files are regularly purged. An IP address is a number designated for your computer by your Internet service provider to provide access to the Internet.  Generally, an IP address will change every time your computer connects to the Internet.  However, if you have a broadband connection, it is possible that the IP address that we may gather may contain information that may be deemed Personal Information.  This could occur due to the fact that by using certain broadband connections, your IP address would not change and could be associated with your personal computer. We may use your IP address to gather aggregate information on use. But we will only be able to identify you individually if we have the means of linking the IP address to you as a particular user. This usually requires access to additional information which we do not seek.

#### 9 - Your rights concerning your Personal Information

In accordance with applicable law, you have the right to request access to the Personal Information that we hold on you, to have any errors in that information corrected, to request that the Personal Information is deleted as well as to object, on request and free of charge, to the processing of your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes.  

Please address your request to the data protection manager by [email ](mailto:help@clarinsusa.com)or to: Clarins Consumer Relations, 1 Park Avenue, 19th Floor, New York, NY 10016. We will address your queries in accordance with the regime established by the applicable legislation. 

#### 10 - Advertising features

Clarins licenses technology to serve advertisements on its own Sites and within its content as that content is served across the Internet. In addition, CLARINS may use third party network advertisers to serve advertisements and third party analytics vendors to evaluate and provide us with information about the use of the Sites and viewing of our content. We do not share Personal Information with these third parties, but ad network providers, the advertisers, the sponsors, and/or analytics service providers may set and access their own cookies, pixel tags and similar technologies on your Device and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including Usage Information. We and our network advertisers may target advertisements for products and services in which you might be interested based on your visits to both the Sites and other web sites. We may use a variety of companies to serve advertisements.

If you prefer to not receive targeted advertising, you can opt out of certain network advertising programs through the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) Opt-Out Page: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Please note that even if you choose to remove your information (opt out), you will still see advertisements while you're browsing online. However the advertisements you see may be less relevant to you and your interests. Additionally, many network advertising programs allow you to view and manage the interest categories they have compiled from your online browsing activities. These interest categories help determine the types of targeted advertisements you may receive. The NAI Opt-Out Page provides a tool that identifies its member companies that have cookies on your browser and provides links to those companies.
